Hey everyone, thanks for listening to
the Grow Your Life podcast. My name is
Jeremiah Kowski and on this podcast I
help coaches, mentors, trainers to scale
their businesses, get more clients, have
more impact, and make more money than
they've ever imagined. Every single
week, I meet with my clients in my
wealthy coach academy program. bonuses
for coaches and course creators
specifically who want to have more
impact and increase their income where I
work with them personally through their
ads, their marketing, their sales
pitches, every aspect of their
messaging, how they reach clients. And
we have people that are total beginners
who are just starting out because we
have all of the training in there that
helps you with everything as well as
people that have been seasoned veterans
even 10, 20 years in in the industry. I
believe that we have one of the best
programs and it's not just my word that
says it. It's our clients that actually
say that we have one of the best
programs that's out there. And so I
stand by what they say. It's not just me
saying it. I believe that if you have a
chance to join our wealthy coach academy
program, it will change your life and
your business. Now today I want to talk
about a lesson I teach my clients all
the time. It's about messaging. What is
messaging? Why is it important? And how
can you optimize your messaging in
today's market? Well, your messaging has
to do with how you communicate with
potential prospects. So, I want you to
think about this. When you're building
your business, there are two stages that
people are at. Number one, you got total
strangers. I call this strangers on the
internet, right? Strangers on the
internet. These are people that you
don't know. They've never met you
before. And quite frankly, they're
probably skeptical about you and what
you're doing. What's awesome is there's
ways to mitigate that through messaging.
Messaging is what allows somebody to
make a decision to become your client to
trust you in a split second after they
just meet you. And I'll tell you this as
somebody who actually struggled with
that for years and now coming on the
other side of it to where I know how to
build trust with people. I know how to
demonstrate my value that I'm walking in
confidence and I have a sevenfigure
business that is changing people's
lives. I understand how important
messaging is. And I also understand when
I was giving mixed messaging. Have you
ever had that before where you give
mixed messages to somebody
inadvertently? You weren't trying to or
let's flip it around. Maybe somebody
else was giving you mixed messages. We
all know kind of the awkwardness that
happens there when mixed messages start
coming into our lives. We don't know is
this beneficial or not? And so because
of that, what we have to do is we have
to
navigate what does this person mean? Are
they being truthful or not? Is there
something behind their words? Is there
something else going on? And oftentimes
this has to do with our tone of voice.
This has to do with our body language.
This has to do with the words that we
say. But it also has to do with the
words that we write. And all of that
combined together equals your branding
in your business. I think a lot of
people think of branding as logos and
colors and websites and graphics and
things like that. That's not really
branding. Real branding has to do with
the experience that somebody has when
they first meet you. Do they feel like
they are being seen and heard? And
that's where your messaging comes from
is you're able to demonstrate that you
understand the needs and goals of the
prospects that you have. You understand
what they're going through and somebody
who really truly is trustworthy in the
marketplace knows exactly what their
clients are dealing with. Now, I'll tell
you this, my track record, I've been in
this industry for 22 years. I knew
exactly what my clients needed at all
times. But here's the problem. my
struggle with my messaging. It's because
I got caught up in my head in
perfectionism. It wasn't because I
lacked trust or the ability to build it
or lack the experience. I didn't know
how to get it from here and here brain
heart coherence to coming out of here
and the written word that I was typing
because I was constantly getting caught
up in my head in overwhelm about what
are people thinking about me or let's
let's say this maybe you're not worried
about what people think about you but
you want to do things the right way.
Ah, see now we're touching on something
that I think every single one of us can
understand is we have a desire to do
things the right way often and we don't
want to do it the wrong way. Of course,
none of us do. But this desire ends up
leading us to
actually suffering and not being able to
dial in our messaging simply because we
get caught up in the potential scenarios
of what might go right or wrong by what
we say and how people might perceive us.
And so we're trying to do all the right
things and we literally get caught up in
our head
around am I saying it right? Am I doing
it right? Do I have the right body
language? Am I showing up right? And
then our desire to actually get our
messaging dialed in literally shows up
as somebody that people don't trust. Let
me explain
this. There's a difference between being
open and joyful and fluid and free and
excited and you have vocal inflections
that go up and down while you're
communicating with people. And then
there's a difference between being
locked up,
tense, timid, scared, nervous,
afraid. And whether we're actually know
if we are scared, nervous, or afraid, if
our body language is reading that way.
So you have to understand the real part
of it has nothing to do with necessarily
how you feel
inside. It has to do with how it's
perceived. And again, I'm telling you, I
know. I understand this can make your
brain spin in a circles and go crazy
like feeling this way. I have a
shorefire way that has actually helped
me with my messaging is number one I
focus on calming my nervous system down
to where I feel confident in myself to
where I feel unstoppable unshakable to
where I'm not worried what everybody
thinks and I know that I'm having an
impact and that I'm excited to share
what I have to share with everybody and
that I start using my body language and
my my tone of voice my tonality and now
All of that combined together goes into
one fluid communication format where, as
you can see here on my podcast, when it
all kind of comes together, feels very
natural, feels
very great to listen to. Um, it's it it
connects with people. I feel like I'm
connecting with you right now. If you're
listening to this right now, we're
making a connection. We're not on a
private Zoom call or anything, but
there's a connection that's being made
where I'm understanding what are you
going through, what are you dealing
with, and I'm communicating, okay, do
this, do that, do this, do that, and I'm
painting a picture for how to dial your
messaging in. So, that's phase one of
the messaging is tonality. Anytime that
you're marketing or building your
business, whether it becomes your social
media content, your sales pitches, your
emails, by the way, when you're writing
your emails, when you're writing sales
copy, when you're writing captions for
your social media, all of this comes
into play because if I'm writing a
caption from a place of I'm nervous, is
this going to get the algorithm to make
me go viral and all this type of stuff
like this, I'm actually not going to
show up as the best version of myself in
that. Whereas, if I'm more fluid and I
just want to share with people and I
want to connect with people, it actually
comes across way better in that
way and if I'm doing a sales pitch and
I'm less, okay, I hope that I say all
the right things, I follow the right
script, I'm following the right format,
oh gosh, I don't want to mess up. Or if
I'm just fluid and I'm just having fun
with it and I'm just sharing what's
going on. If I'm recording a podcast
that way, if I'm writing an email to
people, making a YouTube video, making
an Instagram reel, whatever it is, if
I'm doing it from a place of it's fluid,
I'm
relaxed. And I and I like to combine it
relaxed and
excited. I think that like if you can
like embody both of those emotions, it's
it's kind of like imagine that you are
at your
favorite experience of all
time that you've been waiting for for so
long. Everything is taken care of. You
have no
stress. Maybe you're on a beach
somewhere and you're not worried about
anything, but you're excited about what
you get to do. There's an energy that
literally comes across there. It's it it
kind of if you've ever been on a
vacation, it is like a vacation mindset
that you show up with. And if you can
literally embody that and you can get
your brain into that state of mind right
away, you the words that you write, the
sales copy, your Instagram reels, your
YouTube videos, your sales pitches, all
of that. What I do when I get
into recording podcasts, when I record
content, when I write sales copy, I try
to get myself into really that vacation
state of mind. One of the things that
has actually always helped me with this,
and I do it less and less nowadays than
I used to, but I still I still enjoy it
from time to time, playing video games
because I've always whenever I have
nothing else to do, I got all my chores
done, quote unquote, I sit down and I
like to enjoy a video game. Now, as a
dad with two kids and I got a growing
business, there's not as much time for
that. So, I found that I've shifted some
of those things into other areas to
where I find that enjoyment in just the
ability to maybe to listen to a podcast
or process things or or just to clean up
the house a little bit. I actually find
some enjoyment in cleaning my house. You
might find that yourself in whatever
those things are that it inspires you.
Get something done that makes you feel
accomplished in something, that helps
you feel excited, whatever your thing is
in that stage. In my season before I had
kids, it was playing video games. Now,
literally, I before I recorded this
podcast, I literally did the dishes for
the last
hour and did baby bottles and cleaned up
the whole kitchen. Like, it looks
amazing. And now I'm ready to share with
you because I feel on fire because, hey,
listen, I created an environment for my
family that's incredible. See, you think
about that and it shifts from season to
season as far as that goes. What gets us
excited in our lives, it's different.
Now the second part of it messaging wise
has to do with a little bit of the more
technical sequence is where chat GPT can
actually come in and you can use AI to
help you with your written
messaging. And really I use kind of two
AI resources more than anything else. I
use Chat GPT and I use Claude AI. Claude
AI is really great right here. Chat GPT
is right here. Um, I actually use a tool
called po.com which contains both of
them for one low price of $20 a month
that you can use, which is amazing. It
gives you all of these different
algorithms. I got
GPT4 03, which is the state-of-the-art
intelligence bot. We got Google Gemini.
Forgot to mention that one. That one's
super intelligent as well. Uh, Deep Seek
Llama. And again, you might be like,
"What are these? I don't know what those
are." Listen, if you hang around me for
a little while, understand this. Claude,
I love Claude because it's great at
writing emails. For everything else, I
like using GPT40. If I'm writing sales
copy or I'm writing maybe social media
content, I might use DeepSeek
R1 and I'll use 03 for processing big
picture ideas. That's kind of how I use
the different AIs out there. Okay, so
remember that Claude as of today Claude
3.5 or 3.7 for writing emails. Really
great at writing emails. Use DeepSeek R1
for social media captions. I find it's
really great for social media captions.
Use
GPT40 to write sales copy for landing
pages and offers that you're creating.
And then use 03 chat
GPT03 to process big picture things. I
use it to help me if I'm processing my
emotions or using it to learn new
things. It's the most intelligent as far
as that goes. It's not the best at
writing, but it is the smartest and
that's what I like to use if I need a
little bit of smarts. If I need one of
the most, honestly, it is actually a PhD
level intelligence. They've tested it
out. It's incredible in multiple
domains. 03 is my kind of my go-to now
for most of that type of stuff. Okay,
but let's go back over to Chat GPT.
ChatGBT can help us with our messaging
in this sense is that if we have an
offer that we're trying to create, it
can help us write it. So, let's just say
write a sales letter in a
conversational, informal, and persuasive
tone. Now, right here, I want to pause
tone. We've actually reverse engineered
multiple of the best marketing
campaigns. They all are in a
conversational, meaning it's like we're
having a conversational. They're in an
informal,
nonprofessional tone. You don't want to
sound uber professional. You want to
sound down to earth and persuasive.
Persuasive is what's getting people to
want to buy from
you. I want it to be about my credit
repair coaching business. Let's say that
that's what you coach people on. I'm
hosting a
free training plus a credit repair PDF
guide. By the way, this is one of the
best types of offers that people can
create. Combine a little maybe 15, 20
minute free training with a PDF guide.
This is a great lead magnet for you
right there. create the sales letter
that I can market with Facebook ads,
Instagram, Instagram ads, and social
media content on Tik Tok and Instagram
reels. Okay, great. So, this is going to
give us a sales page around a credit
repair coaching business. And listen,
you could literally fill in any niche or
topic into a prompt like this to help
you write a great sales letter.
Okay. Hey, real talk for a second. If
you're stressed out around your credit
score, dodging phone calls from
collectors, you're not alone. Most
people have never been taught how it
works. You get thrown into the adult
world with no manual, and you're one
late payment away from financial stress.
It ends now. I'm hosting a free
training. I'll teach you step by step
how to repair this. Okay, great. Gives
you bullet points. Honestly, this is
actually a really great beginner sales
letter. And that's what's amazing is
with our messaging, this can help us
write a lot of our sales copy, things
like this. But I want to dive deeper. I
want to go a little bit deeper with
this. Can you expand upon
this even deeper around pain points,
desires,
frustrations, goals, dreams, aspir
aspirations of the
prospect, write PAS and ADA copy and
then talk about
benefits, multiple
benefits instead of features.
All right, we're going to list all of
these
out based on
this. I just want my life back. Let me
guess. You've been starting on that
credit repair journey for a long time,
wondering why it never moves. You've
watched Tik Toks and YouTube videos, but
feel stuck. And deep down, you're
asking, "Am I ever going to make it?"
Bad credit keeps you stuck. Stuck
renting. Start paying big interest. You
try to explain it to people, but they
don't get it. You feel embarrassed.
solution. Try our offer. Your credit
score is not your worth, but it is
blocking your future. Most people don't
realize this. Okay, great. Core
belief. I can finally breathe again.
These are benefits. I know what to do.
I'm in control. Respect. Freedom. All
right, we can turn this into short ads.
Now if you can write this as an epiphany
bridge story of three different people
who went from where they are to the
final outcome goal and every step along
the way of the hero's journey finding
our offer. Okay. So right here we're
literally breaking down like the hero's
journey of the offer of somebody who
found the offer. Single mom who wants to
buy a home, worked three jobs with their
kids. The breaking point one day she
said outside rejection crying she
started searching for this inside the
training things finally clicked. Okay.
Andre the entrepreneur who couldn't get
funded. This is great. The couple who
wants to start over. Awesome. Okay.
Final CTA. Now take all of this, combine
it together into a report about three
versions of the target customer. what we
need to talk about related to
outcomes, the top sales copy,
um frame
frameworks, frame this into Dan
Kennedy's,
uh 10 smart
market diagnosis
questions, and then proceed to prepare a
report about the marketing for this
offer. And so again, we're using
multiple prompts in this, but we're
prompting this right away. And by the
way, I'm writing a lot of these prompts
on the fly right now, but this would
help you tremendously to be able to do
something like this. Okay, so you have
the single parent, denied loans,
stability, overwhelmed, distrusting,
scammy repair
services. These are the desired outcomes
to get approved. Top sales copy
frameworks highlight these issues.
Here's Dan Kennedy. Smart market
diagnosis questions. I love this. It has
them all
listed. Will I ever get out of this
hole? More rejection. They're angry
about the credit system. Credit bureaus.
What are their top frustrations? What
are trends that are occurring? What do
they desire? Redemption. Built-in bias.
They're skeptical about gurus. They
already buy solutions. Yeah, they're
going through YouTube and all this type
of stuff. They have their own language.
Messaging strategy. You're not lazy. The
system wasn't built to teach you. Bad
credit. And you could literally filter
all of this
into a simple framework just by
prompting the way that I've shown you
right here. So now what we can do is
write a informal, persuasive and
conversational sales letter that uses a
storytelling
empathizing
framework
of I know what it's like. I've been
there
too. and create a final sales
letter like this. Then rewrite me
another sales letter for this in the
tone of Sandy Kowski. Sandy Kowski is my
mom and her and I wrote a lot of sales
letters together. It's actually trained
on how we wrote a lot of those sales
letters to do this two ways like this.
All
right. Hey friend, let me get real for a
second. I know what it's like to feel
embarrassed every time someone runs your
credit. to sit in a dealership
pretending like you're confident deep
down knowing you might get denied. I've
been there not once, not twice, but for
years. I know what it's like to have a
decent job, good heart, and a pile of
mistakes. It's not laziness. It's not
that you're irresponsible. No one ever
taught you how to navigate it. Here's
the truth. They don't tell you. You
don't need perfect credit. Start fixing
it. You don't need to pay sketchy
companies and you don't need to figure
it all out on your own. This is amazing
because it touches on all of those
points to help you write the sales
letter. And here's the Sandy Kowski
style. Sweet friend, let me say it loud
and clear. Your credit score is not who
you are. It's not your value. It's not
your measure of intelligence. But let's
be honest, keeps you stuck. Stuck
renting, stuck in high interest rates,
stuck feeling ashamed. You've done what
you could. You've worked hard. This is
awesome. So again, right there, this is
going to be great. Uh, yes, turn it
into all of those. It's going to give us
some ideas. It's going to it's going to
map this out as a sales letter. Here's a
heading section. Free training on credit
repair. Emotional hook. Ever feel stuck?
Here's the story. I know what it's like
to feel stuck. Here's the benefits. You
throw in some testimonials. Call to
action. Here's maybe a script for a
video or Instagram reels or a webinar
opener. So, right there again in your
messaging, chat GPT is able to help us
create a lot of those strategies by
putting those things
together. And that gets you further
along and further ahead at writing your
sales copy by learning how to
communicate that in that way. Now, I
actually have a document that I put
together. You can go to
jeremicowski.com/hatgpt to get this
document. And I walk you through how to
write your messaging to be able to do
this. And it really is that simple.
Anytime I'm writing a sales letter,
anytime I'm creating an offer with my
messaging, I go to chat GBT and I give
it this foundation about my business. I
have it brainstorm these things. It
simulates the brain mindset of my client
to be able to do this. And so, listen,
if you do this, if you follow these
types of prompts in your business, this
is going to help you write better
emails, better sales copy, have better
messaging, communicate better with
people by understanding what is the root
behind why people are thinking a certain
way, why they're doing certain things,
and what they're struggling with in your
offers. If you are a coach, mentor, or
trainer, I'd love to work with you
inside of my Wealthy Coach Academy
program. Inside of my Wealthy Coach
Academy program, every single week, I am
working with clients to be able to show
them what to do and how to do it to get
more clients, how to write their ads,
how to write their sales copy, how to
create their messaging, their landing
pages, their sales pitches, their
offers. And I'm in the trenches with you
every single week in our group guiding
you through this. We have a ton of
training in there that covers every
single topic that you can imagine. You
can read our testimonials. I went and
scrolled through those right there. We
have a track record of success that is
unmatched in the industry. And we have a
reputation and I'm really actually proud
of this. We have a reputation. All of
our clients love working with us. They
say that it's the best thing that
they've ever put their money into. And
so I'd love to invite you to go check it
out. Wealthy Coach Academy program at
some point to work with us. You can
actually find one of the links below to
find out how to get started with us in
the Wealthy Coach Academy program. Grow
your life, everybody. I'll see you on
the next podcast episode. We'll talk
soon. Have a good one.
[Music]
[Applause]